# Abhijeet Salunkhe

Bengaluru, Karnataka, India



abhijeetwebdev@gmail.com



9867884320



linkedin.com/in/abhijeet-salunkhe

# **Summary**

I have over 9 years of experience working in web-based product and service software development. I worked in startup environments where I got opportunities to work as a Full-stack Developer, primarily on MEAN and LAMP stack based technologies.

I am a curious learner. I like exploring new technologies and bringing the ideas into reality. I have created prototypes for ideas like YouTube Remote Control, developed a Socket.IO and Arduino based application for an art installation at KalaGhoda Art festival, created jQuery based plugins and Raspberry Pie based interactive applications as well.

#### Competencies,

- Frameworks: Angular, LitElement, VueJS, ExpressJS, NestJS, KoaJS, Flask, Laravel
- Languages: JavaScript, TypeScript, NodeJS, Python, HTML, CSS, SASS, PHP
- Databases: MySQL, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, and Cassandra

# **Experience**

# kyndryl Software Engineer

Kyndryl

Sep 2021 - Present (1 year 9 months)

Kyndryl was created from the spin-off of IBM's infrastructure services business that designs, builds, manages and develops large-scale information systems.

#### Roles and Responsibilities,

- Working as a Full-stack engineer, developing the UI and the API service development of the Catalyst project.
- Developing a web application using IBM's carbon design system and Polymer frameworks "Lit-Flement"
- Following the Redux implementation for managing the application state, using the "Redux-Saga" library.
- Working on the REST API development using Koa.JS framework (NodeJS) and PostgreSQL.
- Also, involved in the business requirement analysis and sprint planning.
- Assisting the fellow engineers in resolving technical issues, reviewing code and following other SDLC practices.

## **IBM** Software Engineer

**IBM** 

Jun 2021 - Aug 2021 (3 months)

#### Sr. Software Engineer

#### **Quess Corp Limited**

Jun 2020 - May 2021 (1 year)

Quess Corp Limited is one of the leading companies in Workforce Management, Operating Asset Management, and Global Technology Solutions.

I worked with client IBM GTS, where I got a chance to work on 2 projects so far.

- 1. Discovery framework development for the IBM RO Platform.
- 2. IAM console for the IBM Catalyst project.

Roles and Responsibilities at Discovery team,

- Built a Python-based CLI tool that automates the RO software solution by executing the Cloud infra discovery, Validation, and Ingestion.
- As a part of discovery, this tool queries cloud infrastructure like VMWare vCenter to gather the information of components like Datacenters, ESXi, Clusters, Virtual Machines, and more.
- As a part of the validation, this tool processes the information and validates against the rules specified in the solution validation template. There's a provision for our service engineer to approve, override, or reject the information for the data ingestion step.
- As a part of data ingestion, the tool executes APIs calls or the CLI scripts on a remote RO server to create the components required for the specific solution.

Roles and Responsibilities at Catalyst team,

- Worked on the UI and the API service development of the IAM console of the Catalyst project.
- Responsible for the development of UI components using IBM's carbon design system and Polymer frameworks "Lit-Element"
- Followed the Redux implementation for managing the application state, for that, we are using the "Redux-Saga" library.
- Worked on the REST API development of the IAM console using NodeJS and Cassandra DB.
- Responsible for developing the REST APIs required for the user interfaces and the feature requirements.
- Used CASBIN framework for the User, Roles and Resource management at the backend.



### Sr. Software Engineer/Team Lead

#### **AEIONE LLP**

Jul 2017 - May 2020 (2 years 11 months)

AEIONE (Arts & Entertainment Information Network) is a business-oriented social and professional networking service exclusive for the arts and entertainment industry.

We have built a product "One Page Spotlight", that offers a platform for artists, recruiters, influencers, and aficionados under one roof to realize the goal of bringing the art community closer.

Roles and Responsibilities,

- Worked as a core development team member and lead a frontend engineers team.
- Involved in ideation, design, development, and the deployment process.
- Co-ordinated with the Design, UI, Frontend, and Backend teams to plan a roadmap for the application feature development.
- Assigned daily/weekly tasks and monitored the activity.
- Created the frontend application architecture along with the NGRX based Redux implementation.
- Worked on the Angular framework based frontend development.

- Worked on the backend development using PHP, NodeJS, Cassandra, and MongoDB.
- Responsible for the deployment of the Frontend and Backend applications.
- Conducted code reviews to maintain code quality.

### Sr. Full Stack Developer

#### Penguin Thoughts

Dec 2014 - Apr 2017 (2 years 5 months)

Penguin Thoughts is a Mumbai based organization that deals in Social Media, Branding, Web Design and Development.

#### Role and Responsibilities,

- Worked as a full-stack web application developer.
- Developed CMS based web applications using LAMP and MEAN stack.
- Worked with frameworks like Bootstrap, Unsemantic, Semantic UI, Zurb Foundation for UI development.
- Worked with AngularJS, BackboneJS like frameworks for frontend development.
- Worked with frameworks backend like ExpressJS, Laravel, Codelgniter.
- Mentored the fellow interns and consult them on the development part.
- Involved in gathering client requirements, discussion/ideation with the design team on the UX part to prevent re-work on design and development.
- Responsible for the development, test, and deployment of web applications.



#### Multimedia Developer

#### GlowLogic

Aug 2013 - Nov 2014 (1 year 4 months)

GlowLogic Media is a Mumbai based firm organization provides technology solutions for startups and social media agencies in Mumbai and Delhi.

#### Role and Responsibilities,

- Worked as a web developer.
- Developed websites, campaign microsites using HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, PHP, and MySQL.
- Developed social media campaign based Facebook page applications.
- Worked with Facebook, Twitter, Instagram, Google Maps APIs.
- Responsible for the complete web application development that includes responsive UI, frontend functionality, backend development, and the deployment as well.



#### Jr. Web Developer

#### Social Seety

Jan 2013 - Aug 2013 (8 months)

Social Seety is a Mumbai based digital organization that specializes in providing social media solutions for brands.

#### Role and Responsibilities,

- Worked as a UI developer.
- Responsible for creating interfaces using HTML, CSS, and JavaScript.

# **Education**

# Lord's Universal College

Bachelor of Science (B.Sc.IT), Information Technology 2009 - 2012

# Atmoday Vidyamandir

Higher Secondary School, Science 2007 - 2009

# **Skills**

Angular • JavaScript • TypeScript • React.js • Vue.js • Node.js • Python (Programming Language) • SQL • HTML • Cascading Style Sheets (CSS)